juniper.net 2009-02-23

# Juniper Networks :: Juniper Networks Privacy Policy

### Our Commitment to Privacy

Juniper Networks respects the privacy of individuals who provide us with personal information, including our customers, resellers, distributors, service providers and visitors to our website, and is committed to protect the personal information that is provided to us through our website, by email or by other means. Juniper Networks does not collect or use personal information from an individual unless the individual intentionally provides it and consents to its usage. This privacy policy ("Policy") describes our personal information handling practices and applies to Juniper Networks, Inc. and all of its subsidiaries worldwide.

### Information Collected

Personal information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, social security number, national identification numbers, email address, postal or physical address or other contact information, occupation, industry or other information needed to answer a request, to better provide information and services or to comply with various national, state, provincial or local governmental reporting requirements.

Juniper Networks may collect personal information as described below. In each case, we only collect personal information that we believe to be relevant and required to provide an individual with requested information and services and to conduct our business.

By way of example, we may collect personal information for the purposes set forth below:

  * Viewing of product demonstrations
  * Accessing of white papers (Note: once you have registered for a white paper or tool, you may visit at any time using your password and user ID.)
  * Participation in marketing promotions
  * Participation in seminars or events
  * Career opportunities
  * User surveys
  * Use of "Locate Channel Partner" page
  * Secured Partner sites
  * Registration of products
  * Direct marketing by Juniper or its telemarketing service providers
  * Responding to an inquiry
  * Providing technical support or consulting services

In addition, when accessing certain documents or services on our website or during other marketing activities, visitors may be asked to provide certain information, such as how they can be contacted, where they work, and what they do. We may also track non-personal information about the web pages and content accessed by visitors at the Juniper Networks website and the number of times such content is accessed by a visitor. Juniper Networks collects this non-personal information in an effort to better meet the needs of visitors to its website to answer questions, and to improve delivery of information and services to visitors of the website.

Also, in the course of performing services for customers, Juniper Networks may be provided access to a customer's networks or systems, and in rare cases, may be able to view or receive portions of personal information of customer's clients. Juniper Networks does not and will not use this information, and if indirectly collected as part of the performance of services, all such information is safeguarded in accordance with this Policy.

### Notice and Ability to Opt-Out

When personal information is collected, we will inform the individual at the point of collection the purpose for the collection and where appropriate, allow the individual to elect whether to provide the information to Juniper Networks and/or specify how we can use such personal information.

Juniper Networks provides individuals who elect to receive electronic or other communications the ability to "opt-out" of those communications by sending us a notice to unsubscribe. Juniper Networks respects your wishes and will discontinue communicating with individuals who have requested not to receive email or other communications from Juniper Networks. This means we assume an individual has given us consent to collect and use his/her personal information in accordance with this Policy unless the individual has taken affirmative action to indicate that he/she does not consent, for instance by clicking or checking the appropriate option or box at the point of collection. In some cases, when applicable, Juniper Networks will provide an individual with the opportunity to "opt-in." This means that we will require affirmative action from the individual to indicate his/her consent before we use personal information for purposes other than the purpose for which the personal information was submitted.

### Sharing, Disclosure and Security of Personal Information

If an individual chooses to provide Juniper Networks with personal information, the personal information will be used solely by and transferred only to Juniper Networks, its offices and subsidiaries around the world, its resellers and distributors and service providers, which are those companies contracted by Juniper Networks to deliver requested information and services. We may also transfer personal information across borders and from the individual's country or jurisdictions to Juniper Networks' offices and subsidiaries, its resellers and distributors and service providers around the world. All such entities are governed by this Policy or are bound by appropriate confidentiality and data transfer agreements.

An individual's personal information is never shared outside Juniper Networks without permission, except under conditions explained below. Juniper Networks may send personal information to other service provider companies under any of the following circumstances:

  * when we have an individual's consent to share the information;
  * if sharing an individual's information is necessary to provide a product or service that is requested (If personal information is shared with third parties we will only provide the information they need to deliver the service. Also, such companies are prohibited from using such personal information for any other purpose);
  * as part of a joint sales promotion or to pass sales leads to one of our distribution partners; and
  * to keep an individual up to date on the latest product announcements, product updates, special offers or other information we think he/she would like to hear about either from us or from our service providers (unless the individual has opted out of these types of communications).

We will also disclose personal information if required or permitted to do so by law, or in urgent circumstances, to protect personal safety, the public or our websites.

Juniper Networks safeguards the security of the personal information and other data provided to us with physical, electronic and managerial procedures. Inside Juniper Networks, data is stored in secure and controlled servers with limited access. Your information may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country where Juniper Networks, its subsidiaries or service providers are located. While we strive to protect personal information, we cannot ensure the security of the personal information provided to us. We urge individuals to protect their personal information when using the Internet by, for example, changing passwords often, using a combination of letters and numbers and making sure to use a secure browser.

### Use of Cookies

A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer's hard disk so that the website can remember who you are. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number.

When you visit our website, we send you a cookie. Cookies may be used in the following ways: 

  * To help us recognize you as a unique visitor (just a number) when you return to our website, to allow us to tailor content or advertisements to match your preferred interests, or to avoid showing you the same advertisements repeatedly.
  * To develop leads for our internal sales group and our business partners and provide direct marketing communications to you if you have explicitly consented to receive such communications.
  * To compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our site and to help us improve the structure of our website. We cannot identify you personally in this way.

Two types of cookies may be used on this website: session cookies (which are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the site) and persistent cookies (which remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer, though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie).

### Disabling/Enabling Cookies

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser, as well as delete any cookies that have been installed in the cookie folder of your browser. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of our site if cookies are disabled/deleted. If you do not know how to disable or delete cookies for the browser you are using, you should select 'cookies' in the Help function of your browser to get more information.

### Accessing and Updating Personal Information

Juniper Networks encourages all individuals who provide personal information to Juniper Networks to keep their personal information accurate and up to date. Personal information may in many cases be updated by an individual online. Individuals may also request access to their personal information by sending an email to  .

### Children and Privacy

Our websites do not target and are not intended to attract children under the age of 13. Juniper Networks does not knowingly solicit personal information from children under the age of 13 or send them requests for personal information.

### Third Party Sites

Juniper Networks' website may provide links to other third party websites which are outside our control and not covered by this Policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these third party websites.

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

Juniper Networks may amend this Policy from time to time. If we make significant changes that affect the way we use your personal information, we will notify you by posting a revised statement on this site.

### Questions

If you have any questions about this Policy, please email us at  or mail us at Juniper Networks, 1194 North Mathilda Avenue, Sunnyvale, CA 94089-1206 USA.

_This document was last updated September 4, 2008._
